(GRAND ORCHESTRAL FANFARE
PLAYING)
Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm
♪ ♪
Subtitles by explosiveskull
(WIND WHISTLING SOFTLY)
♪ ♪
(WOOD CREAKING)
(GROWLING)
- Quiet!
- (GROWLS)
(CLICK. FIRE WHOOSHING)
What are you?
Shh.
- (TOOTHLESS GROWLING)
- Oh.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(SCREAMS)
You're a demon!
(SHUSHING)
No. no. I'm not a demon.
I'm not a demon.
See? Just a guy.
Just a guy here to rescue
these dragons. so. uh...
- But you walked through fire!
- Dragon scales!
Dragons shed a lot.
No. I know a demon
when I see one.
No human legs are that skinny.
(HOOKFANG ROARS.
TRAPPER SCREAMS)
Think that's a good entrance?
Get a load of me.
(SCREAMING)
I knew it! More demons!
Ah. it's really just a nitwit
who forgot
to fireproof his butt.
Hot. hot. hot. hot!
- Guys. no. not yet!
- (SPARKS CRACKLING)
(SNOTLOUT SCREAMS)
- Behold. your worst nightmare.
- Behold.
Along with his sister.
who insisted on coming.
That's my intro?
Guys. too soon.
You always come in too soon.
(FISHLEGS SCREAMS. GRUNTS)
Sorry. still getting
the hang of my wings.
Fishlegs. again with the baby?
(CHITTERS HAPPILY)
- This is a raid.
- I couldn't find a sitter.
Demons everywhere!
- It's the end of the world!
- (HELMET CLANKS)
(GROANS)
(CHUCKLES): Astrid. I had him
right where I wanted him.
And now he's right
where I wanted him.
Let's get to work.
HICCUP:
Okay. we screwed that up.
but at least nobody else
knows we're here.
(GROWLS)
Easy. girl. It's okay.
(SNARLS. HICCUP SHUSHES)
We're gonna get you
out of here.
(DOOR CREAKS)
(GASPS)
A Crimson Goregutter!
(HIGH-PITCHED CHUCKLE)
(CHITTERS)
(GROWLS)
RUFFNUT:
(LAUGHS) Look at this weirdo.
Bet it's super-dumb.
(GRUNTING)
Why can't I get this cage open?
It slides.
(SCOFFS) Obviously.
GUARD (IN DISTANCE):
Attack!
- Get the rescues out of here!
- GUARD: Get that Night Fury!
(GRUNTING. BLADES CLANGING)
TUFFNUT:
No running on the deck!
It's slippery.
You could fall.
Step aside! Let me handle
the tough guy stuff.
(GRUNTS. GUARDS CHUCKLE)
- Huh?
- Whoa.
(GUARDS SCREAMING)
- Yeah! That's two for me.
- (HOOKFANG SNARLS)
(ROARS)
- (GUARD SHOUTS)
- SNOTLOUT: Look out!
- No. no. no. no. no. no. no!
- Sorry! (GRUNTS)
(FISHLEGS CHUCKLES.
GUARD SHOUTS)
(GRUNTING)
- ASTRID: Ha!
- (GRUNTING CONTINUES)
- (TOOTHLESS SNARLS)
- Thank you.
Now. go get the rest. bud.
(ASTRID GRUNTING)
I thought this was supposed
to be a stealth mission.
Yeah. they always
start that way.
- Look out!
- (GUARD GRUNTING)
(GUARD SCREAMS. WATER SPLASHES)
ASTRID:
Thanks. Stormfly!
(DRAGONS CALLING)
- (CLOUDJUMPER GRUNTS)
- Oh. stop worrying.
They'll get it.
(YELLS. GRUNTS)
(GASPS)
- Eventually.
- (CLOUDJUMPER GRUNTS)
- (GUARD GRUNTS)
- Move out! We got 'em all.
- I'm gonna headlock every last one of you.
- (RUFFNUT LAUGHS)
- I might even leg-lock you.
- Let's go. let's go. let's go!
- SNOTLOUT: Amateurs.
- I was just getting started.
- ASTRID: Clear out. guys!
- Go. go!
- (GUARDS SHOUTING)
GUARD:
Don't let them get away!
(FISHLEGS WHOOPS)
HICCUP:
Good hustle. boys!
(SNIFFING)
- Toothless. time to go!
- (TOOTHLESS GRUNTS)
- (GUARDS CHUCKLING)
- Oh.
(GUARD GROWLS)
- Hey. guys.
- (GUARD CHUCKLES)
(GASPS. GUARDS GRUNTING)
(ROARING)
HICCUP: (LAUGHS)
You always have my back. bud.
(TOOTHLESS ROARING)
(DRAGONS CALLING)
♪ ♪
This is Berk.
your new home away from home.
A stunning. one-stop.
all-expense-paid
dream destination.
(DRAGON SNARLS)
So. settle in and let
your worries melt away.
The service here soars.
the cuisine is fiery...
...and the locals are
as colorful as you get.
Any run-of-the-mill paradise
boasts beaches and sunshine.
(GRUNTING)
Well. not us.
We've got something
no one else can touch.
- We. my friend. have dragons.
- Make room!
They're coming!
Lots and lots of dragons.
(ROARS)
(PEOPLE SHOUTING.
SHEEP BLEATING)
Gang. meet our latest Berkians.
(ROARS)
Welcome to paradise. mate.
- Our home is your home.
- Well. aren't you a beauty!
- Ah. you're welcome. You're welcome.
- Ah.
I took on. like.
a hundred trappers.
A-a thousand trappers.
(CHUCKLES):
All with burning undies.
- (LAUGHS)
- My thick. full beard almost caught on fire.
Ugh. Just-just stop.
So. uh. Hiccup's mom.
any notes on
my bone-crushing assault.
or was it pretty much perfect?
Oh. it was indescribable.
And please. call me Valka.
It has been a year.
First-name basis.
I think the real hero
of the day was Toothless.
Isn't that right. bud?
What would we do without you.
oh. king of dragons?
- (PURRING)
- What would we do?
Well. we could train
a lot harder. for one.
That was pretty sloppy.
(CHUCKLES)
Astrid. uh. does have a point.
Perhaps you all rely a little
bit too much on your dragons
and not enough on one another.
See? That's exactly
what I was saying.
Just listen up. guys.
Yeah. your mom's
super impressed with me.
I'm like the son
she always wanted.
- (YAPPING)
- Fishmeat.
You found a new friend.
(GRUNTS)
(ROARING PLAYFULLY)
- Mind your heads!
- Whoa! - Oh!
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(FISHMEAT CONTINUES YAPPING)
(ROARS)
(DRAGONS SQUAWKING)
(DRAGONS SHRIEKING)
(GROANS) What good is having
the king of dragons around
if he can't keep the order?
Hey. bud. do you want
to do something here or...?
(ROARS)
(YAPPING)
(GROANS SADLY)
And where do you suppose
we put these ones?
Ah. we'll make room.
(GOBBER SCREAMS. HICCUP GRUNTS)
- You brought back a Hobgobbler!
- (SNORTING SOFTLY)
They're a bad omen.
We're cursed.
- (LAUGHS)
- VALKA: Nonsense.
What harm could he do?
No injuries.
They're all a little shaken
but otherwise healthy.
Now. who's hungry?
(LAUGHTER. LIVELY CHATTER)
(DRAGONS SQUAWKING)
Point is you can't keep
bringing dragons back here.
- (SCREAMS)
- Come on. boy.
You're just asking for trouble.
No. you don't.
you little thief!
Those trappers are
getting closer by the day.
We can handle them.
We have the alpha.
Ain't that right. bud?
Would you look at
how happy they are?
(BOTH GRUNT)
- (VALKA LAUGHING)
- She's awesome.
Gobber. relax. We did it.
The world's first
dragon-Viking utopia.
We made the dream a reality.
Your dream maybe.
Mine's less crowded and more...
(HOBGOBBLER CROAKS)
(SCREAMS)
...sanitary.
Gobber. you're not
fooling anybody.
I know you love them.
(TOOTHLESS GROWLS)
(SNARLS)
(YELPS)
You're supposed to be
the generation
that leads us into the future.
(LAUGHS) Food fight!
- (GRUNTING)
- Ooh. gorgeous.
- Watch the hair!
- Good. Fishmeat.
(MAKES EATING AND KISSING
NOISES. GRUNTING CONTINUES)
- Ugh! God help us.
- Right between the eyes!
Time to stop worrying about
problems out there...
- Gobber.
- ...and start sorting out the ones right here.
- (ASTRID GRUNTS)
- (MUFFLED): Okay. okay.
I-I'll think about it.
Hang up those saddles
and get married.
- (CHATTER STOPS)
- The "M" word.
Gross. Unless it's me.
(GRUNTS)
Start ruling like
a proper royal couple.
- Marry him. please.
- (MUFFLED GRUNTING)
You're the only one
with any sense around here.
With you wearing the pants.
there's still hope.
- Wow!
- Gobber...
- Not awkward at all.
- (HICCUP GRUNTS. COUGHS)
- Astrid. don't be like that.
- (TUFFNUT CHUCKLES)
Whoa. That is a definitive no.
Look. if you need
a beard to cry on.
just lean on my shoulder
and you can cry into
my full. thick beard.
(MUFFLED):
Oh. thank you. Tuffnut.
Thank you.
- So much.
- (ERET CLEARS THROAT)
Eret. son of Eret!
(SPITS. GROANS)
What's the report?
Two more trapper barges
spotted in the strait.
So we go after them.
- What?
- One day.
you're gonna pick a fight
you can't win.
♪ ♪
(WHOOSHING)
(DRAGON GROWLS)
(DRAGONS CALLING)
GUARD:
Archers!
(DRAGONS SNARLING)
(METAL RATTLING. MEN MURMURING)
- Dragon killers.
- Stay on your guard.
Deathgrippers.
(MEN CLAMORING)
(DRAGONS ROARING)
(CLAMORING CONTINUES.
DRAGONS SNARLING)
(SHOUTING)
Back! Do what I say. now!
Do what I say!
Grab the other head
on that Zippleback!
You belong to the...
The dragon riders
attacked us here.
off the Eastern Strait.
(IMITATES SHIP EXPLOSION)
- Ragnar.
- Um. sorry.
My dear warlords.
How go your plans
to conquer the world?
(LAUGHS)
Grimmel. my old friend.
- Thank you for coming.
- (ROARS)
Oh! (GRUNTING)
A year since Drago's defeat.
and no further along
with your dragon army. I see.
You can thank the young chief
of Berk for that.
Stoick's boy?
(GRUNTS) Yep. he and his
peace-loving dragon riders
continue to raid our ships
and steal our dragons.
Mm. That does sound
like a nuisance.
But I'm in the business
of killing dragons.
- not retrieving them.
- (SIGHS)
- But. Grimmel...
- That idiot boy has done
all of the work for you.
gathering the dragons
in one place.
Why bother me?
Because the flock is protected
by a Night Fury.
Not possible.
(CHUCKLES) It seems one slipped
through your fingers.
Look. Berk's dragons
will follow the alpha.
So we'll pay you to capture him
and bring the flock to us.
(SINGSONGY): We even have
your favorite bait.
The only dragon they left us
from last night's raid.
A female? Hmm.
(COOS SOFTLY)
So. do we have a deal.
old friend?
(ROARING. MEN CLAMORING)
Watch out!
- (DRAGON BREATHING SLOWLY)
- When all is said and done.
this young chief will
bring me the Night Fury.
They don't have a leader.
just a boy.
STOICK (ECHOES):
Hiccup.
(WIND WHISTLING SOFTLY)
This is Berk. son.
- It's our home.
- (SEAGULLS SQUAWKING)
It was the home
of your grandparents
and their grandparents
before them.
And it's my job as chief
to protect us. Hiccup.
And one day.
when you're all grown up.
that job will be
passed on to you.
HICCUP:
Okay.
And it's very important. son.
because out there.
beyond the sunset.
lies the home of the dragons.
- Wow.
- Aye.
Legends tell of ships
that sailed too close to it.
only to drop off
the edge of the world.
- never to be seen again.
- (GASPS)
But those sailors
who turned back
told tales of a great waterfall
and dragons guarding
the entrance to a Hidden World.
- Whoa.
- Not just a nest. Hiccup.
but a land from which
all dragons come.
Even Night Furies?
(CHUCKLES):
Especially Night Furies.
(SHUDDERS)
Those are scary.
Don't you worry.
One day. I'll find
the Hidden World
and seal it up.
so that people and dragons
will fight no more.
(DRAGONS CALLING IN DISTANCE)
(TOOTHLESS GRUNTS)
What?
(GRUNTS INQUISITIVELY)
Oh. all right.
You do know it's not
a chew toy. don't you?
Is this what you want?
Oh. do you want this leg?
Do you want my leg?
(GRUNTS) Go get it.
(TOOTHLESS GRUNTING HAPPILY)
Getting pretty good
at gliding on your own. bud.
(GRUNTS. PANTS)
(STORMFLY SQUAWKS)
Oh. so this is where you come
to get away from Gobber.
I have no idea
what you're talking about.
- Ugh.
- (STORMFLY SQUAWKS)
Well. he's right. you know.
R-Really?
You think you and I should...?
Oh. gods. no.
We're nowhere near
ready for that.
No. that's-that's crazy.
I mean. he's right
about all of this.
(SIGHS) It does seem like the
whole world knows about us now.
Yep. And the more dragons
we bring back here.
the bigger of a target
we become.
Ugh.
I just wish there was some way
to make them leave us alone.
There might be.
Dad used to talk about
an old mariners' myth.
of a secret land
at the edge of the world
where dragons live
totally out of reach.
(CHUCKLES) Well. sailors are
known for tall tales.
True. But what if it's real?
It could be the answer
to all of our problems.
How? By moving
the dragons there?
Uh-uh. All of us.
Seriously?
And abandon our home
of seven generations?
- The home your father left you to protect.
- (SIGHS)
Uh...
Yeah. I think we need
a real solution. Hiccup.
(STORMFLY SQUEALS)
(TOOTHLESS GROWLS)
Well. we could just
take Gobber's advice
and tie the knot.
That should fix everything.
But. hey. if you're having
doubts about yours truly.
- I'm pretty sure Snotlout's available.
- (CHUCKLES)
He only has eyes for your mom.
(GASPS. GROANS DRAMATICALLY)
- Playing dirty now. huh?
- (CHUCKLES) You asked for it.
Looks like there might be
a wedding after all.
- Oh. how dare you? That is a low blow.
- (LAUGHING)
No. no. you are not
getting away.
(GROANS)
Okay. okay. you win. you win!
- You always win.
- (LAUGHS)
You knew what you were
getting into.
- Uh-huh. Right.
- (DRAGON CALLS IN DISTANCE)
(DRAGON CALLS IN DISTANCE)
Uh. bud?
What... Yeah. sure.
don't bother to wait for us.
(SIGHS)
(SNIFFING)
(DRAGON CALLS IN DISTANCE)
♪ ♪
(PURRING SOFTLY)
(COOS SOFTLY)
(SNIFFS)
(PURRING SOFTLY)
(GRUNTS SOFTLY)
(SQUAWKS)
(GRUNTS)
(GROWLS. HISSES)
(SNIFFING)
(SHUDDERS)
(BOTH GRUNTING SOFTLY)
(TWIG SNAPS IN DISTANCE.
DRAGON SNARLS)
(DRAGON GROWLS)
Oh. my gods.
- (DRAGON YOWLS)
- Uh. Hiccup!
- (GRUNTS)
- Oh!
(TOOTHLESS GROWLS)
Yeah. yeah. w-we're friends.
No need to kill us.
(DRAGON GROWLS)
(YELPING)
(ROARS)
(EXPLOSION ECHOES)
(GROANS SADLY)
- (CHUCKLES): Wow.
- Another Night Fury.
No. not quite.
It's more like a...
- Bright... Fury.
- A Light Fury.
Yeah. yours is better.
probably.
(GROANS SADLY)
SNOTLOUT:
What do you mean. gone?
- Vanished. into thin air.
- (FLIES BUZZING)
- What do you think?
- Uh-uh.
Stubbier ears.
No dorsal plates.
- FISHLEGS: Okay. Got it.
- (ERET CHUCKLES)
What a night.
- Bud. what's gotten into you?
- (TOOTHLESS PANTING)
What is all this
slobbering and panting?
Isn't it obvious?
He's in love.
Trust me. relationships are
nothing but pain and misery.
(ASTRID SCOFFS)
What did I just say?
A-Am I not enough?
(GRUNTS)
I think that's a no.
(DRAGONS PURRING AND WARBLING)
(PURRS SOFTLY)
- FISHLEGS: Something like this?
- You know what?
Just trace your Toothless card
and make her white.
- You could've led with that.
- ASTRID: Can you believe it?
Toothless has a girlfriend.
I never took you
for a romantic.
Like. ever.
(CHUCKLES)
But it's so sweet.
I mean. look.
(PURRING)
(CHUCKLES):
Okay. That's just sad.
- And weird.
- Yeah. you better do something.
Seriously? I'd rather shovel
poop all day than watch that.
All right.
Let's head back to the woods
and see if we can find her.
(GRUNTING HAPPILY)
Ah. good idea.
(QUIETLY):
A little privacy.
- Uh...
- Shh.
- It's boy talk.
- What?
Come on.
let's go work this out.
TUFFNUT:
So. you want to get married.
- HICCUP: Uh. no. actually.
- (CHUCKLES. SNIFFS)
Good news.
I've been to two weddings.
I crashed both. but none
as high profile as this one.
Lots of pressure. judgment.
and not just by me.
Look. we talked about it.
We're not getting married.
Cold feet.
I've seen it before.
Don't worry. Little Hiccy.
I'm here.
Wait. Hiccy?
Now. I've seen the way
Astrid looks at you.
Everyone has. That doubt.
That not so subtle
disappointment.
That longing for something
more than you.
You need to focus on
being worthy.
I mean. she's a warrior queen.
for Thor's sake.
And you are neither.
But with me as your best man...
your spirit guide.
if you will...
you'll learn to embrace
your inner Viking.
Show these naysayers.
of which there are many.
that you're more than
just a malnourished runt
with bad hair. strange teeth.
and a twig for a neck.
HICCUP: You're-you're
really bad at pep talks.
Stop letting these insecurities
- get the best of you.
- (SNIFFING)
Everyone's watching.
I mean. everyone.
You need to man up.
Do as I do.
It'll be hard.
but you have my word.
And until I break that word.
I won't give up.
Hey.
Hey! What. am I wasting
my time here?
You see some shiny thing in
the woods... Ooh. what is that?
(GROANS SADLY)
- Toothless!
- (GROWLS)
Don't move a muscle.
Hey!
(TUFFNUT AND HICCUP GASP)
(GROWLS)
(PANTING)
- Someone's here.
- Huh?
He managed to slip
past our scouts
and lay a trap in the woods.
- It ruined boy talk.
- (GASPS): Oh.
- Gah. let me at him!
- Slow down. Gobber.
Let's get a search team on
the ground. scouts in the air.
Toothless and I
will fly the coastline.
Yeah. I wouldn't advise taking
Toothless anywhere. Chief.
I know this handiwork.
Grimmel the Grisly.
Famous back where I'm from.
The smartest dragon hunter
I ever met.
Well. next to me. of course.
Well. he can't be that smart.
He left his trap unmanned.
(CHUCKLES) Nothing's accidental
when it comes to old Grimmel.
He lives for the hunt.
to get inside the mind
of his prey.
to control its every choice.
It's all a game to him.
Well. he doesn't know
who he's playing with.
Yeah. Well. we've dealt with
his kind before.
Don't underestimate him.
Hiccup.
Mark my words.
He'll be back.
Then we'll be waiting for him.
(BLOWS)
(QUIETLY):
All right.
All right. come on.
give me a clue here.
Give me a clue. Dad.
(WOOD CREAKING SOFTLY)
(QUIET SNORING)
(QUIET TAP)
Oh. I hope you don't mind
if I help myself.
This is. uh. mmm. quite good.
Oh. that is impressive.
But let me finish my drink.
(GRUNTS)
Toothless!
(SIGHS)
What did you do to him?
Eh. nothing
that he won't sleep off.
(SIGHS. CHUCKLES)
May I?
Chief Hiccup.
Hmm? Do I say Chief (HICCUPS)
or do I call you Hiccup?
What do you prefer?
You have no idea
who I am. do you?
Oh. (CHUCKLES)
Well. your father knew of me.
Now. there was a chief.
One of the greatest dragon
hunters to have ever lived.
What would he think of you?
(GRIMMEL CHUCKLES)
He had it right. you know.
Making it his mission
to destroy the beasts
so that you could grow up
in a better world.
He changed his mind.
And look where that got him.
So let's get to the point.
I am the Night Fury killer.
I've hunted
every last one but yours.
You are going to give me
that dragon. or I will...
I will never give him up.
(LAUGHS)
You wish dragons to live free
among us like equals?
A toxic notion. my boy.
History has shown that we are
the superior species.
What if word of your
misguided ideas were to spread?
It would be the undoing
of civilization
(SLOWLY):
as we know it.
Hmm.
Did we get him?
(SIGHS WOOZILY)
Now!
Sorry to barge in.
You think you can
come into my home.
sit in my father's chair.
and threaten my dragon?
This is Berk.
And we have defended our way of
life from far worse than you.
Ooh. (CHUCKLES)
A fighting spirit.
I love it.
Only I'm afraid
you're mistaken.
You've never seen
anything like me.
(WHISTLES)
(ASTRID GASPS)
(DRAGON ROARS. ASTRID SCREAMS)
(ASTRID PANTING. DRAGON SNARLS)
Astrid. look out!
(ROARING)
(GRIMMEL LAUGHS. HICCUP GASPS)
(WHISTLES)
VALKA:
Look out! Son. get clear.
(DRAGON ROARS. ASTRID PANTING)
- Run!
- (FISHLEGS GROANS WEAKLY)
(VALKA GASPS)
(VALKA STRAINS)
- (HICCUP COUGHING)
- GRIMMEL: Have my dragon ready
when I return. or I will
destroy everything you love.
(HICCUP COUGHING)
(CROWD CLAMORING IN DISTANCE)
- Grab the buckets!
- How did this happen?!
(CROWD MURMURING.
THUNDER RUMBLING)
- Inside.
- It's the middle of the night.
- What are we doing here?
- HICCUP: All right.
All right. everybody.
Settle down. please.
- Fishlegs.
- (GRUNTS WEAKLY)
Have you ever seen
that species of dragon before?
(HIGH-PITCHED SIGH)
(GROWLS):
Let me at him!
I'll give him
a piece of my mind!
- And by mind. I mean fist!
- (GRUNTS)
Did you miss the part
where we almost died?
- Have you seen my house?
- (CROWD QUIETS)
This is a new kind of enemy.
And I underestimated him.
Now. that's on me.
But I will not do that again.
(GRUNTS) We're Vikings.
We don't run from a fight.
At least. I don't.
You might.
I agree with Hiccup.
We haven't seen
the last of Grimmel.
He's a predator.
single-minded and patient.
He won't stop
until he gets what he wants.
I'm with Eret.
We have to take
this threat seriously.
Grimmel is just
a sign of the times.
Our enemies are getting
smarter. more determined.
We're not just overcrowded.
We are exposed and vulnerable.
Short of full-blown war
and risking everyone we love.
I don't...
I don't see a way
of staying here any longer.
- (CROWD GRUMBLING)
- What would Stoick think of this?
- Hey! Hear him out!
- (CROWD QUIETS)
If we want to live in peace
with our dragons.
we need a better plan.
So what are you saying. Chief?
I'm saying
we have to disappear.
- Off the map.
- (CROWD MURMURS)
Take the dragons to a place
where no one will find them.
And where might that be?
He's talking about a quest
for the Hidden World.
The hidden what?
- Out to lunch. - Yeah.
- (BOTH CHUCKLE)
My father was obsessed with it
when I was a boy.
He made notes and maps
in search of the ancestral home
of all dragons.
tucked away somewhere
beyond the edge of the world.
It may be the solution we need.
We are dragon people.
- It's where we belong.
- (CROWD GRUMBLES)
Look. I know this is our home.
My father left me
to protect it.
But Berk is more
than this place.
We are Berk.
The people. the dragons.
I say Berk is wherever we go.
- (CROWD MURMURS)
- MAN: I don't know.
What do you think?
I'm with him! Who else?!
♪ ♪
(CROWD CHATTERING)
(BLEATING)
(DRAGON GROWLS)
(DRAGONS SQUEALING AND CALLING)
FISHLEGS:
Excuse me. Coming through.
Just. let me just
get right through here.
Fishmeat. look. eat your rocks.
Eat your rocks.
Gods! People who fly
with babies are the worst.
(FISHMEAT SNARLS.
SNOTLOUT GROANS)
I feel like I'm always asking
you this question. but...
- (SNORING)
- (GASPS) Wake up. Grump! Wake up!
Is there an actual plan or...?
Just keep flying until
we reach the end of the world.
Ah. Seems sensible.
CHAGHATAI KHAN:
So. where are they?
Gone. Obviously.
The Night Fury escaped you?
- Again?
- I encouraged it.
They've abandoned
their only defensible position.
Running scared
with what little
they can carry.
(GROANS)
It just keeps going.
That's 'cause the world
is actually round.
- The sun's round. The moon is round.
- (ASTRID LAUGHS)
- Stars are round.
- (TOOTHLESS GRUNTS)
Even though
they're small and stupid.
- (LAUGHS)
- Right? Stars.
Don't fret.
They won't get far.
The Night Fury is distracted.
I introduced him
to your female.
Furies mate for life. you see.
- (TOOTHLESS GRUNTS)
- What you picking up on. bud?
(GRUNTS HAPPILY)
(GASPS) The Light Fury!
- She's following us!
- Wow!
Cool.
(LIGHT FURY SQUAWKS)
- GOBBER: Would ya look at that?
- TUFFNUT: Where'd she go?
- Is she made of sky?
- (TOOTHLESS ROARS)
HICCUP:
Whoa! Hold up. Toothless!
(TOOTHLESS PANTING
AND GRUNTING HAPPILY)
- Well. look who it is.
- (LIGHT FURY SHRIEKING)
Uh... (GRUNTS)
Oh. hey. it's really nice
to finally...
(SCREAMING)
(PURRING)
(LAUGHTER)
SNOTLOUT:
This is perfect. So great.
Not a word.
(PURRING)
RAGNAR: Y-Yes. yes.
but where did they go?
(SIGHS):
I have to explain this.
Night Furies can't survive
in the cold.
so they haven't gone north.
They're trying to put distance
between themselves
and enemies to the east
and south.
And Night Furies cannot fly
long distances without rest.
Their flight path
must include stops.
Potty break!
GRIMMEL:
Therefore. they've gone...
(DRAGONS CALLING)
They can only have gone...
Does anyone want
to take a guess?
Anyone?
(STUTTERS MOCKINGLY):
W-W... W-W-W...
Ah. east!
West.
Hmm? Simple. you see?
Oh. isn't this fun?
Yes? No?
(GRISELDA GROANS)
- Yes. Yes.
- (RAGNAR GROANS)
Where is your love of the hunt?
I thought you were conquerors.
You'll have your prize in time.
Just allow me a few more days
to enjoy this.
I have dearly missed it.
HICCUP:
All right.
Looks like we're camping here
for tonight.
Well. thank Thor for that.
Yes. My own place.
I plan to build a hut.
only for the bearded.
Ruffnut. you got to stay out.
Chin whiskers don't count.
SNOTLOUT: I see a tower of
manliness in the shape of me.
It's gonna be taller than Eret
with bigger muscles.
W-What?
- Get out of my house!
- Hey.
- Is there a problem here?
- Yeah. there's a problem.
Ever since you showed up.
you've been trying
to upstage me.
You're just so jealous.
It's delusional.
Yeah. delusion's
a good word for it.
Listen. son of Eret.
When Hiccup blows it as chief.
I'm next in line.
Number two. 'cause
I'm clearly Valka's favorite.
So. you better start
showing me some respect.
(ERET CHUCKLES)
Strange little man.
Ah. don't mind him.
It's not your fault you have
the body of a Norse god.
I myself have the same problem.
(BACK CRACKS. GOBBER SCREAMS)
- (SIGHS)
- MAN: This one's mine.
Blacksmith's stall
goes right here.
(SCREAMS)
One. two. three. four. five.
- Where's...? (GASPS) Oh.
- HICCUP: Uh. okay.
Uh. hold on. gang.
I-I said make camp.
- Did you see them?
- Not build a new village.
Who died and made you chief?
- (OTHERS GROAN)
- What? Ow!
Granted. this place
is very nice.
but it's not the Hidden World.
We don't even know
if this Hidden World exists.
- Yeah. This place is real.
- (CROWD MURMURING)
Eh. there's nothing
more stubborn
than a mob of
tired. hungry Vikings.
(SIGHS) Well. I guess this can
work as a base in the meantime.
It's defensible. hidden.
All right. You can stay.
Say hello to New Berk!
- (CROWD CHEERING)
- Let's get building. lads.
Until Toothless and I
find the Hidden World.
- (CROWD GROANS. BOOS)
- MAN: Get off it!
Now. about that voice.
Can we lose the whole
honking goose thing?
It's hard to imagine
wedded bliss
with that going off
every minute. (LAUGHS)
If you're going
to continue west.
I should head back to make sure
we weren't followed.
Great idea. I'll go with you
for protection.
No! You're far
too important here.
Yeah.
Just be careful.
MAN: Look at this place!
It's amazing!
- MAN: That's a nice rock.
- What?
This plan to hide us
from the rest of the world.
Though-though I wish
it were possible.
I fear it can't last. Hiccup.
I mean. you know I tried
to do the same for years.
But greedy humans
always find a way.
I just... I only ask
that you think about it.
MAN:
This one's mine.
GOBBER:
I threw my axe down first.
Do you still think
I'm crazy or...?
Let's just say
this whole idea is very you.
Well. thanks for
supporting me last night.
It meant a lot.
(CHUCKLES)
Don't thank me yet.
I just hope
you're right about this.
- MAN: I like it here.
- I always wanted a sunset view.
(PEOPLE AND DRAGONS SNORING.
CRICKETS CHIRPING)
(HICCUP AND TOOTHLESS SNORING)
(PANTING)
(TOOTHLESS GRUNTS. PURRS)
Toothless.
No. it's too early.
(SNIFFING)
(GRUNTS)
(HICCUP CONTINUES SNORING)
(TOOTHLESS GRUNTING SOFTLY)
(SNIFFING)
(GRUNTS)
(GRUNTING HAPPILY. PURRING)
(YOWLS)
(TOOTHLESS GRUNTS.
LIGHT FURY GROWLS)
(PURRS)
(SNIFFING)
(PEOPLE SNORING NEARBY)
(GRUNTS)
(BOTH PURRING)
(PURRING CONTINUES)
(BOTH GRUNTING SOFTLY)
(GRUNTS)
(YAWNS)
(PANTING)
(LIGHT FURY CALLS)
(SQUAWKS)
♪ ♪
(GRUNTS)
(GROWLS)
(GRUNTS HAPPILY)
(PANTING)
(GRUNTS SOFTLY)
(PURRS)
(TWIG SNAPS)
(GRUNTS INQUISITIVELY)
(PURRS)
(PURRING)
(GRUNTING HAPPILY)
(SNEEZES)
(GROANS)
(GRUNTS)
(GRUNTS SOFTLY)
(SPUTTERING CALL)
(GROANS)
(PURRING AND WARBLING)
(SNORTING)
(GROANS)
(GRUNTS DEEPLY)
(LIGHT FURY YOWLS)
(GRUNTS)
(GRUNTS SOFTLY)
(BRANCH CREAKING SOFTLY)
(BRANCH CRACKLING SOFTLY)
(GRUNTS)
(GRUNTS HAPPILY)
(BRANCH CREAKING)
(GRUNTS SOFTLY)
(TOOTHLESS GRUNTING)
(LIGHT FURY GRUNTS)
(PANTING)
(SQUAWKS)
(GRUNTS)
(GROWLS)
(SNORTING SOFTLY)
♪ ♪
(GRUNTS INQUISITIVELY)
(GROWLS SOFTLY)
Oh. now you can draw.
(BOTH GROWLING)
(PURRS)
(BOTH PURRING SOFTLY)
(BOTH SNIFFING)
(LIGHT FURY PURRS SOFTLY)
(WHINNIES SOFTLY)
(GRUNTS)
(BOTH CALLING)
(SNARLS)
(PURRS)
(GRUNTS)
(ROARS)
(SQUAWKING)
(GROANS)
(TOOTHLESS GROANS SADLY)
(SIGHS)
(TOOL CLINKING QUIETLY)
(CHATTER IN DISTANCE)
- Oh. Someone hasn't slept.
- Yeah.
Well. that Light Fury won't
let me within a mile of her.
And neither of us
will be getting any sleep
or finding the Hidden World
until Toothless takes over.
Hey!
- What do you think of that?
- (TOOTHLESS GRUNTS)
- Yeah. (GRUNTS)
- (GRUNTS HAPPILY)
You tried this once before.
He didn't want it.
(SIGHS) Well. until now.
he didn't have a reason to.
Right. bud?
- (CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
- What?
No. nothing.
I'm-I'm impressed.
I mean. look at you.
Embracing change.
I am proud of you.
Well. he's my best bud.
I want him to be happy.
Eh. besides. it's just
until he brings her back.
(SIGHS)
- All right.
- (GOBBER SIGHS)
- Fire when ready.
- Oh!
Well. I guess you know
the tail is fireproof.
- Okay. Toothless.
- (GRUNTING HAPPILY)
- Okay. okay. Okay. yes. I know.
- (GOBBER GRUNTS)
I know. (SHUSHES)
- Okay. I know. (GRUNTS)
- (PURRING)
- Please. this is not helping.
- ERET: Well. well. well.
Someone's excited.
(SIGHS) He's fresh off
his first date.
Now he's love crazed.
Only we're the ones
going crazy.
The sooner he brings back
that Light Fury. the better.
Yeah. but to do that.
he'll need to fly without me.
So time to give this
new and improved baby a shot.
(PURRS SOFTLY. SNIFFS)
Attaboy.
Looking sharp. Toothless!
So what do you think. bud?
Bring her home.
(IMITATES STOICK):
By sundown at the latest.
(GROANS) No. save it
for your girlfriend.
Go on. Get out of here.
(CHUFFS)
(GROANS SADLY)
It's okay.
(GRUNTS)
(ROARS)
♪ ♪
(GRUNTS)
(LEG SQUEAKS)
- (SPUTTERING SIGH)
- (OTHERS GRUNT. COUGH)
(WHISTLING A TUNE.
LEG SQUEAKING)
♪ ♪
(PANTING)
(VALKA GRUNTS)
♪ ♪
(GASPS SOFTLY)
(GASPS)
(DRAGON SNARLS. VALKA SHOUTS)
(VALKA GRUNTING)
- Watch out!
- (DRAGONS ROARING)
Go. Cloudjumper!
(WHISTLING IN DISTANCE)
(WIND WHISTLING SOFTLY)
(TOOTHLESS CALLING)
♪ ♪
(CALLING)
(GRUNTING)
(GROANS SADLY)
(EXPLOSIVE WHOOSH IN DISTANCE)
(GRUNTS)
(GRUNTS EXCITEDLY)
(PURRS)
(PURRS SOFTLY)
(GRUNTS)
(GRUNTING)
♪ ♪
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(THUNDER CRACKING)
(GRUNTS SOFTLY)
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLES)
(PURRS)
(GRUNTS)
(ROARS)
(GROANS SADLY)
(PURRS)
(SNARLING.
ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
(SHRIEKING)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(GRUNTS)
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
(BURPS. GROANS)
(LIGHT FURY WHINNIES. SQUAWKS)
♪ ♪
(LIGHT FURY PURRS)
(BOTH PURRING SOFTLY)
(GRUNTING SOFTLY)
(WATER RUMBLING)
(RUMBLING GROWS LOUDER)
♪ ♪
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(CROWD CHEERING.
FESTIVE MUSIC PLAYING)
- To the chief! (WHOOPS)
- (LAUGHS)
GROUP:
To the chief!
- Aye. To our chief.
- (CROWD CHEERS)
- Oh. a chip off the old block.
- (HICCUP CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY)
Yeah. okay. guys.
Now I'm just getting sick.
Okay. (CHUCKLES)
- (RETCHES)
- Got to say.
I thought you were
well off your rocker.
but this spot ain't half bad.
This was supposed to be
a temporary solution.
It's unanimous.
Everyone agrees
we've definitely traded up.
- Well done. Chief.
- (FORCED CHUCKLE)
What if the tail broke?
- What if Grimmel found him?
- (SIGHS)
- What if he needs me?
- Would you relax?
He's probably having
the time of his life.
How would I know?
She never comes around.
And when she does.
she's always rushing off.
- I'm saying how-how do we know
- (GROANS)
if she's right for us?
- Us?
- You know what I mean.
She's so wild and skittish.
I'm just gonna say it.
I don't trust her.
(LAUGHS)
Can't tame 'em all. Hiccup.
One day. you'll have to snip
those apron strings
and let Toothless
stretch his wings.
Reminds me of a talk I had
with Stoick about you.
(SCREAMS)
(SNORTING)
Where do they keep coming from?
- Who?
- Those bloody Hobgobblers.
I swear they're popping up
faster than rabbits.
I think they want to eat me.
Evidence would suggest
I'm tasty.
Hiccy. a moment?
Listen. I've been
watching you walk. (SIGHS)
Lose the limp.
No one's gonna marry that.
- (CHUCKLES)
- I have a prosthetic leg.
- So have I.
- And I have a parasitic twin.
but you don't see me
limping around about it.
Come on. Chin up. Hiccy.
Puff out that chest.
- Move that butt to the left a little bit.
- (SLAPS)
(HOBGOBBLERS SNARLING.
GOBBER SCREAMS)
(CLOUDJUMPER ROARS.
CROWD CHATTERING)
(CLOUDJUMPER EXHALES HEAVILY)
Mom. are you hurt?
W-What happened out there?
I don't know how.
but Grimmel is tracking us.
Ah! This is all because
of the Hobgobblers.
He has a hundred ships.
maybe more.
with enough cages
for all of our dragons.
(SIGHS)
If Grimmel is
leading them here.
we have to take him
out of the mix.
Uh. and how would we do that?
By going there to capture him.
Capture him?
I'm with him! Who else?!
(HUMMING A TUNE)
(DRAGON SNORING)
(WIND WHISTLING SOFTLY)
(DRAGONS GROWLING)
(SNAPS FINGERS. DRAGONS SNARL)
(GROWLING)
(QUIETLY): Okay. split up.
We'll be harder to catch.
I was thinking we should
split up. just because.
I like your instincts.
What is this?
(GROWLING SOFTLY)
(GROWLING)
(ROCK CLATTERS)
(GASPING. GRUNTS)
(SNARLS)
♪ ♪
(HEAVY RUMBLING. HICCUP GASPS)
(METAL RATTLING)
- (FISHMEAT SQUEALING)
- Shh! Shh! Quiet.
- Quiet.
- GRIMMEL: Where's your dragon
when you need him. hmm. Chief?
Must have forgotten
all about you. (CHUCKLES)
First rule of the hunt:
separate the prey
from its pack.
You've just removed yourselves
from the equation.
- Why are you doing this?
- Really?
I didn't think you cared.
Well. unlike you.
when I was a boy
and I came upon a Night Fury.
I killed it where it slept.
That simple act of courage
made me a hero in my village.
So I decided
to kill every last one.
bringing real peace
to the people of this world.
Until you came along.
preaching that dragons
are something other than
thieves and murderers.
(SCOFFS)
That nonsense dies now.
starting with you.
- But you have dragons of your own.
- (LAUGHS)
- (LAUGHS): These?
- (GROWLING)
They're dragon killers.
drugged into obedience
with their own venom.
Not even your precious alpha
could control them.
They serve me and only me.
Allow me to demonstrate.
(WHISTLES)
Take cover!
(DRAGONS SNARLING)
- Split up!
- (GRUNTS)
Whoa!
(GRUNTING)
- Whoa! Run!
- (SNARLING)
(PANTING)
(GRUNTS)
- (SHOUTS. GRUNTS)
- (DRAGON ROARS)
(VALKA GRUNTING)
Up here!
(GASPS)
(TAIL RATTLES)
(GRUNTING)
(DRAGON SQUEALS)
(ROARS)
- Hurry!
- (GRUNTING)
Go. go. go. go. go!
(PANTING)
Hiccup!
(DRAGON ROARS)
Gotcha.
Go. Cloudjumper!
(DRAGONS ROARING)
Yeah!
- Our hero!
- (CLOUDJUMPER ROARS)
(DRAGONS ROARING)
(HEAVY RUMBLING)
(DRAGONS CALLING.
FISHMEAT SQUEALING)
(SIGHS):
Hmm.
Ugh. he takes
that stupid baby everywhere.
(DRAGONS CALLING)
GOBBER:
God almighty!
Guess we won't be
needing this then. huh?
I led us right into his trap.
Yeah. nice work. Chief.
Right. Ruff?
Wait.
- Uh...
- Where is Ruffnut?
We-we left her behind?
How could you not notice
she was missing?
You ride a two-headed dragon.
Oh. yeah.
I feel like how Ruffnut is
every day: dumb.
Odin be spanked!
This just gets
better and better.
- (OTHERS GRUMBLING)
- Any more fantastic news?
TUFFNUT:
I try to avoid looking at her.
It gives me acid reflux.
O-Okay. guys.
just keep your helmets on.
Toothless and I will find her.
Toothless has
the Light Fury now.
He's probably
not even coming back.
What?
You gave him
his freedom. Hiccup.
What were you expecting?
I never thought
he'd stay away for good!
I-I... (SIGHS)
Look. I'll-I'll figure it out.
I just need more time.
He thinks he has to lead alone.
Well. because
his father had to.
He doesn't realize
the strength you have together.
- Do you still believe in him?
- Of course.
I wish he did.
But he thinks he's nothing
without Toothless.
Then help him
realize the truth.
(STORMFLY SQUAWKS)
- Get on.
- What?
We're going to find him.
Really?
- (STORMFLY SNARLS)
- Everybody. stay put.
We will get Ruffnut back.
Don't worry.
(SCOFFS) Worry?
If they're stuck with Ruffnut.
I'm more worried about them.
(CHUCKLES)
Why the long face?
(LAUGHS)
I mean. mine's long.
but yours is really long.
All face and no brain. like
you got stretched at birth.
Do you have a twin. too?
Tuffnut took up all the room
in Mom's belly.
Otherwise I'd have
a rounder head and more brains.
- That's science.
- (GROANS)
My braids are like
little Zipplebacks. See?
(IMITATES DRAGONS ROARING)
Even the mold spots
look like eyes. It's so cute.
They even have
little horns and everything.
just like Barf and Belch.
Except me and Barf
can't stand Belch.
so they're really just Barfs.
It's warm in here.
I know what you're thinking.
You've never had
a prisoner this hot.
All the boys love me.
Except Eret.
who totally lost his chance.
That ship has sailed. boy.
Sorry.
And Hiccup is
practically married
to that round-head. Astrid.
But Snotlout and Fishlegs.
they're basically my harem.
- (GROANS. SIGHS)
- I just can't choose. you know?
Snotlout's a beefcake but
almost too pretty. you know?
Sometimes I think he's more
in love with himself than me.
There's only room for one
beauty in this relationship.
(CHUCKLES) Fishlegs would keep
me alive longer if I had to
eat one of them. stranded
on some glacier somewhere.
- But he never shuts up about dragons.
- (DRAGON GROANS)
Don't you hate
when people never stop talking?
- Yes. I do.
- They just keep going and going.
Blah. blah. blah.
It's so boring.
- Can't we just feed her to your dragons?
- I'm hungry.
Hey. what do you have
to eat around here?
I'm allergic to fish.
You should know that.
That's all they have
at that stupid new island.
Do you have any clams?
They're like little mouths
with slimy food inside
that's already chewed.
like the way Mom used to do it.
- (CHUCKLES) - Enough!
- (DRAGON SNARLS)
Until I turned 12 and she was
like. "Chew your own food."
And I was like.
"No. I kinda like it."
Most annoying creature
ever to cross my path.
(GASPS) Aw.
Oops. you let the dragons out.
I'm gonna get you.
- No. this one's gonna get you. (LAUGHS)
- Get...
Take him and go!
Please! I beg you!
The Deathgrippers
will have to forgo dinner.
Ew. you feed
your dragons dragons?
- Go!
- Where's your bathroom?
I got to...
(CLICKS TONGUE)
Okay! Gods.
- No wonder you have gray hair.
- (DRAGON GROANS)
Stress is not good for you.
(LAUGHS)
So long. losers!
(STORMFLY GRUNTING SOFTLY)
- Where-where is she heading?
- She's tracking something.
- Aren't you. girl?
- (SNARLS)
There's nothing but
miles and miles of...
(WATER RUSHING)
♪ ♪
A great waterfall.
- At the end of the world.
- (STORMFLY SNARLS)
(HICCUP AND ASTRID SCREAM)
ASTRID (ECHOING):
Stormfly!
(HICCUP AND ASTRID PANTING)
♪ ♪
(SNIFFING)
(SNORTING)
(SNORTING SOFTLY. SNIFFING)
♪ ♪
(CHUCKLES):
Wow.
Look.
♪ ♪
(WINGS FLUTTERING)
(BOTH GASPING)
- Wow.
♪ ♪
(ASTRID GASPS)
(DRAGONS CALLING)
(DRAGON CALLING)
(STORMFLY SQUAWKS. SNORTS)
It really does exist.
(DRAGONS CALLING)
♪ ♪
- Toothless.
- Shh. You'll spook them.
(DRAGONS CONTINUE CALLING)
(ROARING)
(DRAGONS ROARING LOUDLY)
(ROARING LOUDLY)
Now. that's a king.
(LIGHT FURY PURRS SOFTLY)
(BOTH CALLING SOFTLY)
(LIGHT FURY PURRS)
♪ ♪
- We should go.
- (DRAGON GROWLING)
BOTH:
Oh. no.
(ASTRID GRUNTING AND PANTING)
(ROARING)
(DRAGONS GROWLING)
Stormfly!
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(TOOTHLESS CALLING)
(GRUNTS)
(DRAGONS GROWLING)
(GRUNTING AND PANTING)
(HICCUP SCREAMS)
(BOTH GRUNT)
- Go! Go!
- (PANTING)
(ROARS)
(HICCUP PANTING)
I-I'm sorry. bud.
I-I just...
(TOOTHLESS ROARS)
(STORMFLY SQUAWKS)
♪ ♪
(STOICK SNIFFLES)
(HICCUP GRUNTS SOFTLY)
Son.
(SNIFFLES)
You should be asleep.
I was thirsty.
(SIGHS)
Yeah. come here.
(STOICK GRUNTS. SIGHS)
Dad?
Are you gonna get us a new mom?
(STOICK SIGHS. KISSES)
I don't want another.
Your mom was
the only woman for me.
She was the love of my life.
But with love comes loss. son.
It's part of the deal.
Sometimes it hurts. but
in the end. it's all worth it.
There's no greater gift
than love.
(SIGHS)
(TOOTHLESS GROANING SADLY)
♪ ♪
(GROANS SADLY)
(HICCUP SIGHS)
It's okay. bud.
You belong there. with her.
We don't.
(GRUNTS SOFTLY)
And that's all right.
- We'll find a way to man...
- (DRAGON CALLS IN DISTANCE)
(GRUNTS)
(GRUNTS HAPPILY)
- Hey!
- (CHUFFING)
(LAUGHS)
She followed us back!
(BOTH PURRING HAPPILY)
We might not have to
say good-bye after all.
(BOTH PURRING)
That's it.
RUFFNUT:
Woo-hoo! Yeah! (LAUGHS)
- Ruffnut?
- Miss me?
How did you escape?
I annoyed them
till they let me go.
- (LAUGHS)
- Wait. Wait.
- Grimmel let you go?
- So dumb.
They couldn't handle me.
See. everyone thinks
Tuffnut's more annoying. but...
- Wait. hold on.
- Ruffnut. focus.
- Were you followed?
- (RUFFNUT SCOFFS SOFTLY)
I never look back. Hiccup.
(GASPS) Toothless.
- (GRUNTING)
- Toothless!
(SNIFFS. ROARS)
(YELPS)
(GRUNTS)
(LIGHT FURY SQUEALING)
Toothless. come back!
(GROWLS)
(ROARS)
No!
(DRAGONS SQUAWKING)
And now our little game
must come to an end.
(DRAGONS ROARING)
Call them off. alpha!
No reason for her to die. too.
(DRAGON GRUNTS)
(ROARS)
(ROARING STOPS)
What are they doing?
- They could totally take him.
- Not with her life on the line.
(TOOTHLESS ROARING)
Save your breath.
The only alpha
they respond to is me.
(TOOTHLESS GROANING)
- (SIGHS)
- Oh...
don't feel too badly.
You tried your best.
But you are nothing
without your dragon.
(WHISTLES. DRAGONS GROWL)
(CALLS)
(DRAGONS CALLING)
Toothless!
(PANTING)
(DRAGONS CALLING)
Oh. that is
just (GROANS) great!
Now what?
I think it's time for number
two to become number one.
He'll listen to you.
- Don't say it.
- I wasn't going to.
I shouldn't have
dragged you out there.
He wouldn't have flown me back.
She wouldn't have followed.
- Yep.
- (FRUSTRATED GRUNT)
I feel like the same screwup
I was before I met Toothless.
I can see that.
Are you just gonna stand there
and agree with everything?
Well. you're right.
You're back
to where you started.
but I was the first
to believe in you.
And I have watched you doubt
whether you're worthy
ever since.
But you know what?
I am the person I am today
because of you.
I never told you that.
but it's true.
You are the bravest.
most stubborn.
most determined knucklehead
I know.
Toothless didn't
give you that. Hiccup.
- He just made it...
- Easier.
And now it's gonna be
a lot harder.
So. what are you
gonna do about it?
Probably something stupid.
That's the Hiccup I know.
Suit up. gang.
We're going to get them back.
- What?
- He's lost his mind.
Now. that's marriage material.
At last. faithful pupil.
you are ready.
Um. how are we gonna get our
dragons back without dragons?
Trust me.
(DRAGONS CALLING.
TRAPPERS CHATTERING)
- Watch yourselves.
- You're next.
(CHATTER CONTINUES)
Move it.
(ROARS)
(TOOTHLESS ROARS)
Um. that's right. alpha.
No surprises.
(TOOTHLESS CALLS)
(TRAPPERS GRUNTING)
(SNARLS)
So. jump off the cliff
in these.
That's the best you've got?
No. you guys are
the best I've got.
(GASPS) Aw.
- I'm with him! Who else?!
- I'm with...
Ruffnut. that was my line.
- HICCUP: Let's go!
- ASTRID: Try to keep up!
(HICCUP GRUNTS. ASTRID WHOOPS)
(WIND RUSHING)
- (WHOOPING)
- Yeah! - Yeah!
- I'm doing it!
- All right! - Oh!
- (TRAPPERS CHATTERING)
- GUARD: Get clear!
(TOOTHLESS GROANING)
(GROWLS. GASPS)
Aw. (LAUGHS)
You didn't think I'd actually
hand you the Night Fury.
did you?
He's mine to kill.
That snake!
I intend to finish
what I started.
Best of luck controlling them
without an alpha.
HICCUP (IN DISTANCE):
Hold on. Toothless!
- (TUFFNUT GASPING)
- RUFFNUT: Let go!
(SCREAMS) Could've used
some practice!
Ah. I should've
skipped breakfast!
(GASPING)
(GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
Toothless!
(TOOTHLESS ROARS)
- Look out!
- (GUARDS SCREAMING)
Hot. hot. hot. hot!
(SCREAMING CONTINUES)
They're getting away!
(TOOTHLESS CALLS)
(CLOUDJUMPER CALLS)
(ALL GRUNTING)
(WHOOPS. GRUNTS)
(GROWLS)
Perfect timing.
- Put that down!
- I'll take the skinny one!
Game faces!
Yeah. what are you waiting for?
Get in there.
- (SIGHS)
- Yeah!
- (ALL GRUNTING)
- Take that!
(ROARS)
(GROANS):
Ah.
(LAUGHS)
(SCREAMS)
(PANTING. GRUNTING)
(GASPS. WHISTLES)
(SHOUTS)
(ROARING)
- Watch out!
- The dragons are everywhere!
- Incoming!
- Here they come!
- (SHOUTING CONTINUES)
- Incoming!
Take cover!
Where are you going?!
(BOTH GRUNTING)
- Heads up!
- (GUARD SCREAMS) - Thanks.
Look out! (GRUNTS)
Thanks.
(GRUNTING CONFUSEDLY)
(SHOUTING FRANTICALLY)
(WHISTLES)
(STORMFLY SQUAWKS)
(HICCUP GRUNTS)
(GRUNTING. DRAGON ROARS)
(SHOUTS)
(GRUNTS. PANTS)
I'm coming. Toothless!
You still think
he cares about you?
(GRIMMEL GRUNTS.
LIGHT FURY GROWLING)
Let's just see who he follows.
(TOOTHLESS ROARING)
(GRUNTING)
I'm sorry. bud. for everything.
(TOOTHLESS PURRS)
(DRAGONS SQUAWKING)
(TOOTHLESS GRUNTS)
(ROARS)
Now. let's go get her.
- (YELLING)
- Woo-hoo! Yeah!
Number two coming through!
Surprise!
Sorry about that.
Come on. (GRUNTS)
(GUARDS SHOUTING.
DRAGON ROARING)
- All right!
- One more free! Four to go!
(FISHLEGS GRUNTS.
GUARD SCREAMS)
- Try to keep up!
- (GUARDS CHUCKLING)
I got your backs. Oh!
(GUARD SCREAMS. WATER SPLASHES)
Yeah. it's almost like
we're a team. (GASPS)
(FISHMEAT SQUEALS.
TRAPPER CHUCKLES)
- You brought a baby to a battle.
- (GROWLS)
Ah-ah-ah. I wouldn't
do that if I were you.
(DRAGON ROARING. TRAPPER GASPS)
(TRAPPER SCREAMS)
(SHOUTS)
- God. I love that dragon.
- (FISHMEAT SQUAWKS)
- (GUARDS CLAMORING)
- Come on! Come back here!
(GROWLING)
Sorry we're late for the party.
You're right on time.
(THUNDER CRACKING)
(GROWLS. GROANS)
(TOOTHLESS ROARS)
(GROWLS)
That's it. That's it.
(LIGHT FURY GROANS)
How are we gonna get him off
her back without hurting her?
- Fear the facial hair!
- (GUARD GRUNTS)
(GRUNTS)
(SCREAMS)
(YELLING WILDLY)
(GASPING. SCREAMING)
- Oh. I have missed this.
- Me. too.
- Oh!
- (GRUNTS. LAUGHS)
Ooh. See that there?
Aw. Cute.
That's a bad omen.
You're cursed. (LAUGHS)
(HOBGOBBLERS SQUEALING.
RAGNAR GASPS)
(SCREAMING)
(HOBGOBBLERS SNARLING)
Yes! Go on!
Good on you!
(LAUGHS) I guess you're not
so bad after all.
(GROWLING)
(ASTRID CLEARS THROAT.
GUARD GASPS)
(GUARD SIGHS)
(GRUNTS)
(GUARDS SCREAMING
AND CLAMORING)
(GASPING)
GUARD:
Abandon ship!
- (SCREAMING)
- Whoa!
(GASPING)
(SCREAMS)
(GRUNTING)
- Yay!
- Oh. that was awesome!
- (LAUGHS)
- Yeah! (WHOOPING)
♪ ♪
- (DRAGON ROARS)
- Uh. we've got problems.
(ROARING)
- HOARK: Take him down. Hiccup!
- (CROWD CHEERING)
(ROARING)
(TAIL RATTLES. TOOTHLESS ROARS)
We need a better plan.
and quick!
Uh. uh. what are.
what are you doing?
- (ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
- Okay. Okay.
(ROARING LOUDLY)
(CROWD GASPING AND MURMURING)
MAN:
Where has he gone?
(DRAGONS SQUEALING)
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLES.
TOOTHLESS ROARS)
(YELLS)
(GROANS)
(GRIMMEL SCREAMS)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
You'll kill both of us!
Fighting over a dragon?
That's your plan?
(TOOTHLESS GROANING)
This is.
(GRUNTS. SIGHS)
(LIGHT FURY GROANS)
Save him.
(CALLS)
♪ ♪
(SHRIEKING)
(SCREAMS) No!
(GRUNTS HAPPILY)
See? (CHUCKLES)
I knew you'd come around.
(GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
(DRAGONS CALLING)
(CROWD CHEERING)
Yeah!
(HICCUP GRUNTS)
Hey. Good morning. bud.
(TOOTHLESS GROANING SOFTLY)
Here you go.
Boy. you're full of surprises.
(LIGHT FURY COOING)
He's all yours.
(CHEERING CONTINUES
IN DISTANCE)
(TOOTHLESS PURRS)
(BOTH LAUGH)
You know. Eret may be
blessed with brawn.
but. just between us.
you have the brains.
Number one.
♪ ♪
(BOTH PURRING)
(SNIFFS SOFTLY)
(TOOTHLESS GRUNTING SADLY)
You're right. bud.
It's time.
I was so busy fighting for
a world that I wanted.
I didn't think about
what you needed.
You've looked after us
for long enough.
Time to look after yourselves.
(STORMFLY SNORTS SOFTLY)
Oh. Stormfly. my good girl.
All right. Grumpy.
- (GRUMP PURRS)
- Off you go.
So long. you big ugly beast.
I'll miss you.
(FISHMEAT PANTING)
♪ ♪
(WARBLES)
- Oh. Cloudjumper. Oh.
- (GRUNTS SOFTLY)
Go on. bud.
Lead them to the Hidden World.
(PURRS)
You'll be safe there.
Safer than you could
ever be with me.
(GRUNTS)
It's okay.
I love you. too.
And I want you to be free.
(GROANS SOFTLY)
Our world doesn't deserve you.
Yet.
(PURRING)
Go. Toothless.
Go.
♪ ♪
(ROARING LOUDLY)
(DRAGONS ROARING)
(LIGHT FURY PURRS)
(CROWD MURMURING)
(DRAGONS CALLING)
♪ ♪
(GRUNTS SOFTLY)
(SHEEP BLEATING SOFTLY)
♪ ♪
(SNIFFLING)
SPITELOUT:
To the chief and chieftess!
- Yeah!
- (CROWD CHEERING)
PHLEGMA:
Good on you!
Come. cry into
my full. thick beard.
(SOBBING):
It's so beautiful!
- Gross.
- (SOBBING)
Okay. you win.
I like sensitive guys.
HOARK: I thought
it would never happen.
Finally. right? (LAUGHS)
(CHEERING CONTINUES)
♪ ♪
(WIND WHISTLING SOFTLY)
HICCUP: There were dragons
when I was a boy.
(SNIFFLES)
Ah. there were
great. grim sky dragons
that nested on the clifftops
like gigantic. scary birds.
(WATER SPLASHES)
Little. brown. scuttly dragons
that hunted down the mice and
rats in well-organized packs.
Preposterously huge sea dragons
that were 20 times as big
as the big blue whale.
Some say they crawled
back into the sea.
leaving not a bone nor a fang
for men to remember them by.
Others say they were nothing
but folktales to begin with.
Ah. I'm okay with that.
Hey.
Hey there. bud.
Remember me?
- It's okay.
- (GASPS)
(SNIFFS)
(TOOTHLESS GRUNTS HAPPILY.
HICCUP LAUGHING)
(LAUGHS. SIGHS)
Hey. I am glad
to see you. too. bud. (GRUNTS)
He's not gonna eat your father.
(LAUGHS):
Hey!
How's the tail holding up?
Probably could use some oil
and a little fine-tuning.
Look. it's okay.
They're friends.
(LAUGHING)
(GROANS) Cut it out.
Here.
Go on. It's all right.
Come.
He won't hurt you.
Hold your hands out.
Like this.
That's it.
Let him come to you.
(PURRING SOFTLY)
(BOTH GASP)
♪ ♪
(LAUGHS)
(TOOTHLESS GRUNTS)
(ROARING)
(LAUGHS)
(BABY DRAGONS CHITTERING)
(SQUEAKING)
(ASTRID WHOOPS)
(ASTRID LAUGHS. GIRL LAUGHS)
HICCUP:
Legend says that
when the ground quakes
or lava spews from the earth.
it's the dragons. letting us
know they're still here.
waiting for us to figure out
how to get along.
(STORMFLY SQUAWKS)
Yes. the world believes
the dragons are gone.
if they ever existed at all.
But we Berkians.
we know otherwise.
And we'll guard this secret
until the time comes
when dragons can return
in peace.
♪ ♪
Subtitles by explosiveskull
♪ You and I.
we've been through it all ♪
♪ Is it time to say good-bye? ♪
♪ Dry your eye ♪
♪ We have been together ♪
♪ So long ♪
♪ Is it time to let go? ♪
♪ Apart we grow ♪
♪ Soon we will know ♪
♪ You are the reason
to go on living ♪
♪ I need to try things
and be on my own ♪
♪ We'll always be friends ♪
♪ We'll keep our distance ♪
♪ We'll be together
from afar forever ♪
♪ Listen. listen ♪
♪ Within. ooh-ooh... ♪
♪ We have been.
we've been everywhere ♪
♪ To the stars and back again ♪
♪ Yes. my friend ♪
♪ We have seen.
we've seen everything ♪
♪ But will I ever
see you again ♪
♪ My old friend? ♪
♪ Friends till the end... ♪
♪ You are the reason ♪
♪ To go on living ♪
♪ I need to try things
and be on my own ♪
♪ We'll always be friends ♪
♪ We'll keep our distance ♪
♪ We'll be together
from afar forever ♪
♪ Listen. listen. within ♪
♪ Ooh-ooh ♪
♪ Yeah. yeah ♪
♪ You and I.
we say our good-byes ♪
♪ When will I see you again? ♪
♪ You and I.
we say our good-byes ♪
♪ When will I see you again? ♪
♪ You and I.
we say our good-byes ♪
♪ When will I see you again? ♪
♪ You and I.
we say our good-byes ♪
♪ When will I see you again? ♪
♪ Yeah. yeah ♪
(FADING):
♪ When will I see you again? ♪
♪ ♪
(MUSIC ENDS)
Do you want subtitles for any video?
-=[ ai.OpenSubtitles.com ]=-